hi guys i'm delighted to be in
conversation with
three very interesting people who are
also writers
and i am delighted to have published
them at penguin random house india
my name is mili ashwarya i'm the
publisher at penguin random
and like i said i feel quite blessed and
lucky to have three extraordinary
gentlemen here with me this evening
rajesh shivasta who's written his book
news rules of business get ahead or get
left behind
and we have also with us the authors of
the victory project
six steps to peak potential sarah
mukherjee
and anupam gupta so a warm welcome to
all of you
i know we're going to have a cracker of
a session
and uh i think the whole i mean it
starts with the theme the theme is
really interesting you know
how to be victorious and achieve your
full potential while being simple
so i'm going to start off with uh
sorry because you know you talk a lot
about you know how to achieve
peak potential so why don't you just uh
talk a little bit about
your new book and also how uh you
managed to write it in such a short span
of time
and also achieve great success with it
it is already a bestseller
thanks thanks mili great to be here
great to be here with rajesh and with my
co-author anupam
so so the genesis of our book the
victory project the genesis of this book
is
um two and a half years ago anupam and i
was sitting in cafe zoi
in lower parish unfortunately cafes is
no longer open but it's a gorgeous place
for people like us to have just the kind
of cup of coffee you are having
and uh you are shooting the breeze you
are reminiscing about books as authors
do right we are
reminiscing first about uh my 2014 book
gurus of chaos which is about base
that's full fund managers and we discuss
what are the traits which make
a great fund managers are so successful
then we discussed unusual billionaires
the 2016 book that penguin published
which has successful promoters who've
allocated capital very well and anupam
made a very interesting point and open's
point was that
that the trades which make fund managers
successful are very
similar to the trades which make great
promoters successful
and that led to the intriguing thought
that are there
common characteristics across
professions whether it's publishing
journalism sports
dance uh uh finance
are there common characteristics which
make certain professionals outside
success
the question itself was very intriguing
and i remember this was july
2018 and uh we reached out to
ken and we agreed to publish a few
articles on it um
and at that time i think my my coffee
can investing
was doing quite well one of you guys
reached why don't we do a book on it
it took us actually vice very nice and
you know you were polite and saying we
did it in a short period of time
it took us the best part of two years to
get out of the door
but it was a lot of fun writing because
as rajesh i was just discussing
uh i put a lot of myself in that book
whereas
uh unusual billionaires and coffee can
investing was about other people and
other processes
in a way uh victory project six steps to
peak potential is a lot of work anopher
when i have tried to live
for example simple things like build a
routine live a relatively simple
structured life
we put a lot of ourselves in the book
and and you know it's good to see
uh gratifying to see in this difficult
year uh the book having done well
in the publishing market but the genesis
of it lay in that
coffee in cafes which is why i'm a great
fan of
uh uh unstructured chats over cups
you know i am having black coffee right
now so you're bang on with that
uh smart guess sorry so
yeah see both of us you too so yes
there's a great conversation over
coffee and yeah it's you've written
three best-selling books
and yet you know we you talk about how
to keep it simple and
still you know uh achieve maximum
potential you have laid it out in your
book
we'll come to that in a bit um but
i moved to rajesh now
who's also written his debut book the
new rules of business
and rajesh you know you had an intro oh
we have to promote our books all the
time that's
i think become such a feminist job of a
publisher certainly and authors too
so rajesh you had an extraordinary life
you've launched
the most successful brands you've been
again
you know an academic and taught students
and as you say you learn every day
and while you might not admit i think
every person that you touch
along the way or meet along the way you
know uh
also gets to learn a lot from you and
that's what our experience at penguin
random house india has been
so uh what are these new rules of
business tell us a bit about your book
and
and how did it come to life uh
uh hey billy thanks uh hi sarah anupam
uh how did this come to life let me just
share this uh
story with you uh i had a higher purpose
in life
really uh when i was when i
when i started studying so i wanted to
do a little bit more than what was
expected out of me so i made an effort
to get into iit-iim
but after i graduated out i joined
alcoholic beverage and again i made it a
point to do a little bit more than what
was expected
and uh that was way back you know last
century you can see my hair
so even at that time in india had not
liberalized
we had a world-class dream i had a dream
so the first brand that i got offered
was
bagpiper it was number two in india so i
went to my boss and said you know let's
make it number one in india
when we made it uh then i said let's
make bagpiper number one in the world
and we did make it from there uh i had
another
dream to create categories that did not
exist in alcoholic beverages so we
created a premix category which is
gin and lime premix which is blue and
then i said
can i be creative and uh using
creativity
i gave a name to a brand which is very
popular now called mcdowell's signature
i hope you guys have it this evening but
i hope you guys have it
and then i got a chance to revitalize
royal challenge
uh part of that strategy you can see in
ipl so
the logo that you see on virat kohli
was designed by me and design bridge and
then of course
i wanted to re-imagine a industry
category
so deodorant industry uh category was 66
crore in 2002.
i re-imagined it and said i want i don't
want to sell do i want to sell perfume
and the category today is about six
thousand crore it grew hundred times
so emily all these things and this
experience i had across the world
i decided to give up my corporate career
and share this knowledge
in fact wisdom with rest of the world
and therefore i got into teaching
and when i taught the students i would
teach with
unmatched passion so my students asked
me so why
so much of passion i said guys i have
only 10 years to live
and if i can pass on my knowledge then i
can live with you for another 50 years
through you
and then when that happened i got
another idea
why just restricted to students uh why
not you know
reach out to the whole world and
therefore i became an author
and when i became an author today uh you
know i can reach out to the world and my
voice can be heard
so really these were the reasons why i
all my experiences
is what i have put together in the new
rules of business
but the most important part that i wish
to share with you is
uh while i started teaching something
very dramatic happened in 2008
uh the students in iim indore wanted to
know about facebook twitter
tesla starbucks but there were no
textbooks that were available
talking about it there were no case
studies so i
educated myself and i taught these
students this
and when i was teaching them i
discovered one thing
that these companies you know the new
age companies are dismantling the old
rules and establishing new rules in
their place
but across the world traditional
companies are still using old rules
and if you use old rules in an era of
today then it's like using rotary phone
in an era of smartphone
will become irrelevant and this was the
second driving force
for writing this book new rules of
business it gives you the new rules
and if anyone reads it i think uh he
should benefit
no absolutely i think uh this year
particularly has
forced us to learn new things you know
we you you talk briefly about structure
sarah right i mean our whole routine our
life structure
work culture work spaces
have been questioned and we have uh you
know sort of revisited them and
redefined them
for ourselves in our own ways and
uh i mean we you know maybe the things
that probably we would do
few years down the line have been done
this year because of the pandemic
so i think uh new things are something
that we all have to adapt
i'll give you an example of exactly that
really so so let me first tell you
how i saw rajesh's book so until we were
taking domestic flights which is eight
months ago
uh i used to look around and see what up
what are people reading on domestic
lights i'm always very interested to see
what other people are reading
and i saw that several uh uh people
flying spice jet
indigo were reading rajesh's book right
so so it's still in the back of my mind
that local business people sme owners
are reading this book
then when we published the victory
project he reached out by our social
media
and he said this is me and this is my
book and i went to amazon and bought his
book
what struck me about this book is it's a
very unpretentious business book
right if you see the typical american
textbook from a you know u.s business
school author
right the kind of quasi-academic tool
yeah right whereas this has no
pretensions to be a quasi-academic tone
this is a dhandebaga
and just to give you one specific
example which
he's written about and he wrote this
book well before the pandemic
did you go to say the the highways of
our country
you see that the out of office
advertising market has been hammered
right there's nothing there the
billboards are empty
and yet as we know uh online advertising
is boom
right and his point rajesh's point in
this book i'll just read it out
do you spend money in advertising to
create awareness about your product you
don't need to do that any longer
right he said this this book was written
two years ago
right this is written pre-pandemic and
he made it right anybody who spends
money now putting his
physical billboard yeah
no i i think absolutely so i think
there are simple solutions to technology
and changing business scenarios
uh before i move forward i'll just like
to mention that
uh uh all our viewers if you have any
questions for
any of us please put them and send them
send them to us in the chat box and i
will take them up after our conversation
so uh do remember this is your
opportunity to
you know ask anything that you want of
these three amazing people
i'll move on to you anupam now because
you know in my head
uh you i i and i think maybe a lot of
other people also visualize successful
people
uh you know victory with certain
aggression
energy so is it actually possible to be
simple and yet
you know be be that successful
you know is there a clash there in terms
of you know personalities or
is it possible what do you think yeah of
course it's possible i think saurabh is
the epitome of that right i mean he's
aggressive he's energetic
i'm kind of the antithesis out here i
think it is
i i also think that we now live in a
world where multiple things can be true
at the same time i don't think they live
in you know the world
of app of absolutes and that's in fact
that's one point that's raised in our
book
because we were faced with this clash of
ideas right because we came from the mag
from the malcolm gladwell uh school of
thought which says that you need 10 000
hours of practice and then just last
year you remember that there's this book
called range
magnificent book outstanding book that
kind of question that entire logic
and there's this superb interview
between both the authors
you know who actually have differing
points of view there on youtube and i
would
urge our listeners to have a look at
that um
which shows that both can co-exist and
in fact that's what we've written in the
book we've addressed that point at large
uh saying about how you need to have one
area of knowledge but in today's dna
that one area of knowledge
will not be enough you need to
complement that with a lot of strength
and that's why the t curve so i think
it's absolutely possible
for for multiple ideas and multiple
i wouldn't say posterity because that's
kind of off but you can be successful
you can be aggressive you can be
energetic you can be whatever you want
as long as
i think what matters a lot is that your
you know
you have reached peak potential what
form and shape it takes
is a is a different thing interesting
thank you anubham uh so let's get into
you know our
our theme for today so my next question
to you
saurabh is how can we actually simplify
our lives
you know you talk about it in your book
but
please share it with our viewers today
how can we actually
lead a simple life so look i think the
the writing of the book was also my
attempt to find out the answer to this
question
and then a big part of the journey was
discussing these ideas not not just with
anupam
over lots of coffee i think must have
drunk liters of coffee while writing it
but also reaching out to other people
who have sort of achieved far more than
i have so for example harsh marijuana
sanjeev chandani
radio city and what we noticed right
what we have noticed through
the la the journey of writing these
books over the last
six seven years is most people who are
successful are not successful just
because you know god has been kind to
them or they're
blessed with some innate talent maybe
those are true but those are not
necessary but not sufficient conditions
the core of it is having great clarity
about what exactly do you want to do
if i say i want to be you know a
billionaire
and a successful author and a great
pianist and a great parent right
if i if i'm confused in my head about
exactly what i want to achieve
life becomes difficult so one of the
sort of most
uh tantalizing clues to how to be
successful came from a fund manager
friend from mine of mine in california a
couple of years back
so he told me three years back that look
i focus on
just three things my family
my colleagues and my clients everything
else i'll de-prioritize
so i think embedded in the definition of
success
is letting go making trade-offs and
saying here's the narrow set of things
i'll focus in
so in in you know in my case uh you know
i like writing
uh i like working in marcellus and i
love my family and those become the
troika of things i focus on so
in the book we've been very clear that
the the foundation for outside success
uh starts with specialization focus
specialize
and you begin the journey higher levels
skills are what everybody aspires to
creativity so
when anupam and i present the victory
project typically business
the first question is well how do we how
can we be more creative
because a lot of people believe that you
know if i could just do these three
things
tomorrow morning right that's why the
the
whole t-shaped paradigm of
specialization over a long period of
time is there
if you specialize and build a broad
range of interest
the creativity is a is a by-product of
that
right but the journey starts being very
being very clear about your goals
and ironically the lockdown has made
that a little easier
yeah because it cuts off the stimuli it
locks you into your own world and if
you're in your own world you get
frazzled by
you know by watching yeah there's less
distraction and you know you're more
focused
and you really like focus on the
priorities so you know you get
certain clarity of vision and goals
so i think for all the negatives that
many people will remember 2020 for
i'll remember 2020 for the year i really
figured out what matters to me in life
now what results it will bear we will
see in the rest years to come
yes so i'm i'm waiting to see that too
sorry
but it's really interesting how you put
it and i think
you're absolutely right and i think a
lot of people say that first you need to
articulate your goals very clearly to
yourself
you have to put it out there and then
you know work towards it which is what
you're saying as well
um rajesh you've created great products
like you briefly mentioned
uh but my question to you is
does simplicity play a role there how
can simplicity help create great
products
you know you've talked about creating
super cool brands
so could you could you share some
anecdotes about it and how you actually
did it in your
career uh really uh
let me just start off by saying uh if
you keep
you know all business decisions are very
simple it's just that
we need to ask the right question so let
me just start first with steve job
and maybe alibaba jack ma and then i'll
come to my thing but let's start with
steve job
when he when in 203 he wanted to design
a iphone it didn't exist so he called
all his engineers
and said we want to get into
communication device so do you guys have
any questions
now they were all engineers there and
they asked the engineering questions you
know what efficiency effectiveness
uh you know power capacity etc etc
uh then steve job looked at them he says
i want you to do none of that
i want you to create a product with
which people will fall in love and once
people fall in love then we'll figure
out how to monetize it
now this is exactly the simplicity in
decision that is required
now coming back to me uh i have always
kept one decision
in mind to me how do i make customers
fall in love with my brand
and uh take deodorant deodorant is a
very classical example of how
i i came out with it it is very simple
you know in india
65 of people are below the age of 25
and people of opposite gender want to
come together and
body odor drives them apart yeah leo is
is non-negotiable
but the point is the divo that they used
uh internationally and in our country
was actually for deodorant uh you know
because in cold countries
you don't have a bath so you have body
odor and you use
loha to fight loha so they used a
medicated fragrance to fight deodorant
but uh you know even when i was a kid
and all of you put together your mother
my mother would never let me have
breakfast till i had a bath
if i negotiated that i would not have so
body water was never a problem but in
india we had another problem
you know so i thought that in the sweaty
thing if you get a sweat and you're
coming close to your
uh you know your companion and the body
odor is there
then you would feel bad but let's remove
that body odor i looked at it from a
positive perspective
what if you had a mood enhancing
fragrance and your lady partner came to
you
right if it is a good enhancing then her
mood will also get enhanced and she
would never want to go away
and that is how the simple thing you
know solving the problem of the young
indian
males so this is the simple thing you
know how do i get my companion to stay
very close to me
so this is how i did it i really like
the way you think you know because
you're getting into the psychology of
the buyer and actually in
getting into how and why they want it
and in fact at the level of random level
of relationships
and possibly that is how you know great
bands are created
that's true um really in fact people
will never buy what i create for them
so i have to discover uh what is it that
they are absolutely on
what is their need which is just inbuilt
in them and if i can create a product
that actually caters to their need you
know which they just can't say no to
then it works well right so this is one
or for that matter
uh take alcoholic beverage uh so
my insight was you know people feel that
you know you there are those studs you
know in every company who says you know
i understand my whiskey
so i did a small experiment i called the
studs and said you know i have
uh this is to tell you how we made
bagpiper uh you know a leading brand
yeah my desire was what should we do to
make it india's number one and was
number one
should you improve the blend but the
answer was no
and how did i get an answer to that was
very simple i call these studs in the
office
and you know i chose let's say an
international brand
and my bagpiper but what i did was i
swapped the blend
so out of that international brand there
was bagpiper
and in the bottle of international brand
was
uh in the international brand was
bagpiper and in bagpipers
uh international and in front of them i
poured it
and what i realized is when these guys
saw bagpiper coming out of an
international brand they said wow
smooth etc and when they
johnny locker coming out of a bagpiper
they said yeah
that's when i realized the consumer
insight that people
don't drink whiskey they don't drink
blend what they drink is image
now uh millie wants you and so the
bottom line is if you can understand
consumer insight
why do people drink not blend but image
why do people use the odor and not
because i created deodorant because it's
solving a problem they want their
companion to come
close so in each one of this if you ask
the right question you get the right
answer
and it's largely if you can understand
human beings and cater to them i think
you can create
super super duper big hits
and if i could just sort of plug indian
authors at this juncture
what rajesh is doing and this is the
reason uh you know we like
reading books written by indian authors
for for the indian business context is
the business problems of our country are
a little different from the
of the business problems of the western
world unfortunately
the the primary uh business literature
which gets sold in our country is
western
so in rajesh's book there's a beautiful
example of punishment
two weeks back um i hosted another
penguin author
but explained how he wasn't
at that time and they came up with that
concept which
it punished into into immortality which
was the keratometer
yeah the the concept was women are
getting fleeced
their jewelry is impure yeah ganesh put
in every store a character meter just
shorty see cheese
and the brand pivoted to immortality
right yeah and purity
and yeah that's right so he's rajesh's
book cites this business and this is i
think
the core of the new rules of business
right our country is different
whether it's good or bad is a separate
discourse not for us
but if you are able to apply your mind
and hit the difference you know wealth
follows after
can i yes classical example which is
very indian and found nowhere else which
is about arta
so we were the first company at least in
a formal way which wanted
in 1995 all of us were having you know
our mothers went to get game
to the chucky and everything yeah and
the local
we wanted them to have packaged arta but
we had a problem that time ztv in 1994
had just started
right so if you advertise on z tv it
went all over the country
but when we went and understood the
indian market south and north were two
different markets
south was because they it was not an
arta
market but preferred small pack sizes
whiter and finer and they were price
insensitive
you come to north where arta is a staple
diet they preferred large pack size
extremely sensitive if if it was white
it would be maida
and they wouldn't just buy it so they're
two different markets so how do you come
out with the communication which caters
to both of them
when we did a research what we found was
there was one common theme between the
housewife of chennai that time they were
housewife not homemakers
so how about chennai and delhi was
they would buy that brand of anta using
which when they made their roti the
husband would eat more not the children
the husband
so we came out with
so very indian that i just wanted to
share this with you
no no it's quite recently our country is
our own country it's diverse it's
different
and there's so many that like they say
every 100 kilometers the language
food culture clothes changes so you know
it is quite diverse and i think
that is one of the challenges of i think
product manager the brand managers to
make sure that you know
you penetrate into all parts of the
country uh
you know we i would like to talk a
little bit about collaboration now
and you know anupam you've collaborated
with saurabh for this book and it has
been a very successful collaboration
you brought out a best-selling book and
my question to you is
how does simplicity lead to
collaboration
so it's interesting that you say that
midi because collaboration actually is
you know it's kind of the bridge between
the first uh and the next level so you
do specialize simplify spiritualize
and then you have declutter creativity
and family collaboration so there's a
reason why we've kept collaboration in
in the air because unless you've gone
through the rigor of the previous five
processes you're not going to
be you know you're not you will not
achieve that peak potential unless and
until
you uh you collaborate so i think that's
one thing i think sort of in multiple
uh sessions has also said that it that
this realization has come to us
a little bit late um and whenever we've
had guests or whenever we've done any
session this is one
aspect that i think that a lot of people
gloss over because
probably because hero worship is still
so prominent
in our country the belief that one man
is enough you know one man will change
the world one man will leave
the the the ceo is the only thing that
matters virat kohli is the only thing
that matters
in cricket character all these guys you
would think of them as isolated
um drivers of success all our research
the people that we met whatever we've
done
showed us that actually collaboration is
really the key to achieving that you
if you don't you know if you don't learn
that
you're going to remain restricted to
yourself and whatever your body of
knowledge is i think
uh it's also shown up uh in the example
that we've used that
with whether it's already burman or
araman the fact that they moved from
one level to really higher up is a fact
that they could collaborate across the
board with a lot of people
so that's the relevance of collaboration
seen on its own you wouldn't take it
seriously
seen in connection with the previous
five steps it is a final link to
achieving peak potential
and it's interesting right interesting
that there are so few books western or
indian
yeah on the collaborative nature of
success
right most of it is you know discover
your inner hero typo yeah they're all
players and you know people champions
and you know we like this whole uh
big image and if you give
if you feed these books into a society
like ours which is already kind of an
air in ryan type society
where from you know from your crib you
are taught you know do well in the exams
excel number love job nicolo and more
right if you feed these sorts of western
individualistic books to an
end kind of fed society you create
a construct of success which actually
has no relevance
it has no relevance in the practical
world
because in the practical world you ain't
gonna get you know
in my case i won't even even
go downstairs and use the gym unless i
collaborate with others in the building
because
at a point no more than four people are
allowed in the gym now yeah
so forget about climbing mount everest
this aspect right is very interesting i
think it's a very um
what should i say it's a area rich for
research for writing for making money as
to
who can who has figured out
collaboration
most fluidly most optimally right it is
but obvious that
uh outsized uh corporate success for
example say
success of the sort say nation paints on
an hdfc bank attains
has at the heart of it collaborative
routines right which have embedded
inside them trust
but why are some companies able to
attain that level of collaboration
and and trust why aren't others
right this actually is a big big
question that now sort of is you know
eating me up
right because there is a pecuniary
motive
attached to it i confess but i think
it's a very fascinating question
no no i think it is because there is a
lot of uh
untapped potential there so just to
share with all of you you know at
penguin random
house india we have uh we have our
annual awards and one of the most
uh coveted award is for collaboration
actually
the inter-departmental collaboration on
a new idea new project
book it could be anything but that is
something that you know we all buy for
and fight for within the company because
i think in all all aspects
of you know whether it's sports it's
cinema
it's corporate life businesses
government government can't achieve
let's i mean just imagine distributing
the vaccine
to more than 1 million people in the
country in the next few months do you
think
mr modi can do it alone no you know i
think that
you he'll be the best team in the world
to achieve this you know in the time
frame that you know uh he would want
just one point emily i just
sorry for interrupting you but so we
broke the first myth on collaboration
and what sort of said it's not something
that's discussed very often
there is a second one there that we are
focused on in the book and that is the
idea of a team of rivals which was you
know when we were sitting with mani
sabrawal that's what he
you know he posited this and then when
we researched the item
we actually found that to be true now
collaboration you would think
offhandedly is for a ceo to surround
himself with yes men
uh people who agree with him and for
teams to all think together
are all going towards a common goal
that's actually
because unless and until and i'm not
talking about diversity because
diversity has now become a
cliched word across a lot of
organization no
we're talking about people who have very
diverse
and probably contrary views to the
leader
and as long as those people can hold
their own and those opinions are well
formed for well fought for
then they actually improve the overall
result
that's the point of you and the two
examples that we've used out there the
first of course is abraham lincoln
and and the book which is called team of
rivals by doris khan's goodwin
and how he had actually formed his first
cabinet with people he ran against
and that idea was unheard of and then
you and then ramgua wrote very
eloquently about how gandhiji
took you know the first cabinet that he
formed had vr ambedkar was against
again very opposed to what gandhi said
and we all you know so this is how
things say about so this idea that
collaboration needs to be with people
that you love and we are a family and we
are this we are that
see maybe it achieved results that's a
separate school of thought but we've
written
about the team of rivals about having a
team which is very creative
very vibrant intellectually and that
challenges the leaders with new thoughts
and i completely agree with you because
that's the whole idea of having a team
a team of clones is not really a team
you know so you need
team so i said i say this in my team all
the time you know
i need a team because i need different
voices different people and together we
make
something better than one person would
so i think difference of opinion is very
important and you should respect each
other as professionals
and not it shouldn't be always top down
so i think that's very important and you
know it's one of the learnings that i
think corporates
in india also discovering very fast uh
you know we have a lot of questions i
think now in the chat box but before we
move on to that
i have um you know one final question
for rajesh
uh because you know we we have spoken
about this a bit as well and you
talk a lot about communication you've
written about that
in your book as well uh you know about
low cost yet high impact communication
and and a lot you know we're discovering
or rediscovering that this year
because everything is digital you know
especially in publishing or in the areas
that i have dealt with
it's all about our emails our you know
digital chats how we present ourselves
how we present our products
so uh tell us a bit about that rajesh
uh really just uh one thing i want to
add to what all three of you were
discussing about diversity that's
very important to me one other thing
that i want to say is this concept of
reverse mentoring
uh because i'm with students and young
people uh
anupam and sarah the
way they view the world is very
different than the way i view my world
for example uh this webinar if it was to
be hosted by
young comic my son is a comic their
language and their
their conversation would be entirely
different and therefore one
thing that i just want to say this is a
reverse mentoring is a very very big
thing in 21st century particularly now
for all of us
merely coming to uh this digital you
know this
this part of the digital media all i
got to say is is very simple most of the
companies believe
even till today that the way to build
brand
is to spend money uh i believe that's
not really required it's really not
required
and the reason why i'm saying that is
not really required is because there is
something
which let's say steve job and elon let
me just say uh
model three i think none of us have seen
a single ad
of tesla model 3 but the world knows
about
it he did not even advertise but the
world had one thousand dollars
they opened up their wallet to give it
to him why did it happen
it only happened because he believes in
something which is which i call it the
alternate media
which is basically called buzz pr
event and digital media uh so
what what is buzz buzz is the customer
speak
pr is media speak event of course we all
know and then of course the digital
media that happens and digital media
are of three types paid on and earned so
my entire perspective
is that if we were to intelligently use
uh uh you know alternate media we would
do it so just coming back to elon musk
what does he do
when he has model three he holds an
event in
in in in san francisco press comes
they write about it when we
hear what they write we start speaking
about it which is buzz
and then of course you know twitter and
facebook go up in flame
so my entire perspective is is is this
that we ought to do that the second part
that i wish to say is uh
three or four things one is called
native
content in the sense that you know if i
want people to
read my book and i keep on saying read
read read people will get bored so i've
been following that on social media
i take one contemporary concept that is
happening in the world around us
and then i say this is what is happening
in the world if you want to know more
you can read my book and this is what it
is
so this is what i would say that in 21st
century you don't require money
what you require is ideas you don't
require to spend money is my uh bottom
line and everything
wonderful so i will jump into questions
now um we have several in the chat box
and i think yeah just if you can just
tell everybody that they need to post
their questions in the q a box that
just it'll just make your life that much
easier not in the chat box sorry
sure so you know to all our viewers
listening
and uh you know watching a conversation
today please send all your questions
in the q a box and i think it's already
in the q a i have i think about 10 11
questions but
i'll try and take as many as i can today
so the first one is for
uh saurabh and anupam and puneet
parekh says i love reading victory
project
what is the best way to avoid noise
declutter
your life and keep limited sources of
information
that's got to feel like if if i were to
make a top five questions that we've got
so far in this what six or four months
or we're in the six four months of uh
of talking about the work that has to be
in the top three i'll go first i'll you
know um
see it's simpler than you think it is
yeah i mean and i think the idea
uh of living in eighties life was given
to us by mohanda spy who's there in the
uh he's he's there in the forward of the
book so just go back to the 80s
lifestyle
what did you do i mean assuming that you
were born in the 80s
statistically half of india's population
was born after 1990
uh 1991 if i'm right that's why we have
the democratic division
so anyway so i think first and foremost
you need to just
take that mobile phone of yours and you
know
probably detox a bit that's the first
thing second thing is question the
sources of
news and views that you're getting and
what are and what is actually more
important to you and just let go off of
what you can't see 24 hours is given to
every human being on this planet
neither you nor me are any special we
don't have 30 years saurabh doesn't have
40 hours
or neither of us has you know 15 hours
so that's within that time frame
you just bring down your level of news
and you increase your level of knowledge
use the smartphone for things other than
whatsapp and social media
and use it say to have a kindle on your
book you know
on on your phone you can do your reading
out there so that's the first thing
second is the routine i mean nothing
beats the routine sorry picks up at five
gets a good two hours of reading in
before he
he starts his day so i think those are
the two things use technology in a way
that enriches you and second would be to
you know to to have a routine in those
24 hours and stick to it
i'm sorry i think i just
second what most of our anupam said so
we had to sort of
look at the book and give you sort of
three takeaways which which have
benefited us
um the fact that whether you look at
india or you look at the
world outside uh it does look like
anybody who
manages to achieve outside success does
have a structured routine
so it's a lovely book that we have
quoted from called daily rituals by a
guy called mason curry
he studied the lives of famous authors
architects scientists and so on
and he says that you know there isn't
anybody uh who's been an outside success
without a
reasonably structured routine even
bohemian people like musicians and
painters seem to have a
pretty structured routine the second one
is uh this this
social media thing basically any form of
two-way communication the more you can
get rid of it
you know whatsapp social media even
email
cal newport has written a great book
called digital detox on the subject of
how to cut yourself off from anything
which is
two-way communicate and the third piece
is goals be very clear what exactly do
you want from your life because that
then keeps your focus
but all of that being said it's easy for
us to say these things how i usefully
effectively
do it is a different matter yeah yeah
and really just one thing okay i
i just want to address because i don't
want to come across as someone who's
anti social media
i'm on twitter and i'm pretty prolific
out there so it would be tough
yeah that's what i said yes yes
it would be after me to you know say
otherwise so here's the thing
if you can curate the content that
you're getting whether it's mainstream
media whether it's social media
i think you can actually benefit from
technology right now if you have to use
twitter i don't use notification at all
for any social media out there
if you are on twitter be very cognizant
of who you're following in the media
that you're getting
and you will probably discover a whole
big world of content out there through
twitter if that is your main source of
information
social media also include things like
medium things like sub stack
so there's a lot of good stuff happening
in social media provided you know what
you're there for so
and you know i've i've got this a lot i
used to do digital strategy for
fairly large corporates back in 2014 the
thing is that everybody looked up on
social media as
a place where you have to make an impact
and you have to broadcast yourself
while that may be true social media is
an outstanding place for you to get
very high quality content if you curate
your list properly
so i think that is the first thing and
the second thing got sort of said about
two-way stuff you know
i often find a lot of people uh who
who read a lot but i feel that's just
one part of the story
i mean if you don't have an output for
your views and put
it out there i think that kind of is the
other part of the story maybe you can
find some authors
you know from from the people who
believe very passionately uh
in what you do sort of is a great
example um
the work that marcellus does today in
terms of investment thinking
is actually out there in the public and
marcellus is selective
yeah i think you know you can't miss it
i get regular emails from you guys and
and it's there's a consistency yeah
quality
and remember that marcellus is also on
twitter so if you're someone who's
following marcellus
on on twitter you're sorted you know if
you'll you'll get the best quality
content out there
so i think you need to just find a
balance out there somewhere no i think
uh
you what you said is very true besides
you know having your goals
straightened out and having a routine i
think it's also about the choices we
make
you know with social media it is about
choices because every
every month there'll be new stuff so
what is it that you want and what is it
that makes sense for you and your you
know
goals is what you should focus on i'll
move on to the next question now which
is from
uh weber jawali and it's slightly
related to
you know what uh you know we're
discussing just now in this world of
unlimited noise and distractions how do
we make efforts to
just focus on doing it what we are best
at after figuring
figuring it out so who would like to
take that rajesh i think
this yeah that's what i really want
rajesh's view on that yeah how do we
figure it out first
and then like achieve it his son is an
outstanding stand-up comic i mean he is
at a different level so i'm sure that
you know
go and rush it all yours uh so let me
just give it a business perspective
uh i think life is very simple and
sorted uh provided
provided you have a single minded
perspective so in my case
uh the reason why i exist and the reason
why businesses exist is for no other
reason except for customers
my entire job is to make my customers
happy and delighted and everybody in the
company is actually
entrusted with that job that's it
therefore uh what happens is whenever we
have to take a decision we always ask
one question will it help the customer
yes or no if it does we go ahead and do
it
that is one second thing is just coming
back uh again you know to this
information overload i basically believe
the more
information that comes in uh what i do
is uh
i read a lot right but after reading a
lot i process it in my information
and i squeeze out everything right and
convert it into bite-side wisdom
and i store that wisdom in story forms
and therefore
in colleges or in b schools or in forums
like this when i have to narrate i don't
give
a strategy but in a greater story which
has the strategy embedded in it
so i basically believe that although
there is so much of deluge of
information that is coming in
but what we got to do is take in the
information as much as possible of the
kind that we want
right and then uh reflect on a lot of it
and then squeeze out
all the thing that is unwanted and just
store
uh whatever is there in story formats
which we could
narrate to that is the way i have looked
at it and to me
uh i have never failed in that so
this is the way i look at it wonderful
the next question is i think for sarub
um so it's some c
i i don't have the full name here but
the question is
can you please share your advice for
would-be authors
say who write business and management
related books about how to approach the
publishers
and how best to get the publishers
agreed to publish them scripts
and would you please name any specific
publishers
be very careful sarah who specialize in
business and management
books so look i think i think
i think it's the generic advice uh on
books uh uh
uh ended up speaking to a lot of book
clubs as we
as we've been trying to uh tell people
about the victory project
and there seems to be this received
notion out there
that you know when you write your book
you should sort of think about the
market
and how can you maximize the market it's
like it seems like a very commercial
affair
and and to our mind that doesn't quite
work right it's a very competitive
market really you know how many books
are published every day
on amazon from what i can see every day
20 books are coming onto the market
so if in a typical year 500 600 uh
books are coming into the sort of
quality english publishing space
you're not going to make a mark if you
try to robotize and orchestrate
some sort of uh you know structured
commercial agenda
a simpler way i reckon for for you to
publish a book which will do well
get you the satisfaction and the
recognition you desire
is choose a subject which you feel very
passionate about either you're working
in it or you
you've been very interested in the
subject read up everything that is
available on it
go and meet 20 30 people who know 10
times more than you about the subject
and then i think you'll form the kernel
of an idea of a
interesting book on that subject but
it's going to start with
your interest rather than the the
commerciality of the book
and and you sort of heard this several
times for people that they try to make a
book commercial
unfortunately people like millie will
tear you apart if you're trying to you
know be commercial in front of her
yeah i'm going to just sounds
interesting i'm going to just interrupt
you because you know and i have
absolutely no credibility
as an author you know i was just very
lucky to be part of the don't say that
no no no no i mean don't be i think
don't worry
about simplicity not too much humility
is not good
yeah but i mean it's for real so millie
here's the thing
if i were you know um unusual
billionaires was and
and this is because the person asking
the question mentioned business and
management
so and i'm going to throw this to you
right unusual billionaires was published
by penguin in 2016.
yes till then i can't think of
a single corporate study in india
and to put things in perspective the
outsiders which is considered a pretty
popular book was published in the us in
2001.
now you've got to just think about that
for a moment that why hasn't
the topic of corporate life cycles
been more enriched investigated and put
in the form of books in the indian
domain
i can think of a couple of reasons one
is the fact that uh book writing is not
seen as something lucrative
and and second the kind of books that we
have in corporate
uh in the corporate domain are either
you know autobiographies or puff pieces
or probably scandalous things that
probably sell well and you know they
they have a reason for that
second obviously is the fact that indian
i think indian business is still not
very comfortable about
a searing uh study into
them so if you want to look at
business and management my suggestion
would be to have
a look at slightly you know at topics
that have that haven't been spoken about
till date i mean that's what i would
have to say i just like to add
one more thing here milly uh if you
really want to write a book
then let it not be googleable that's the
first thing
second thing that i would say is that
people are not interested in hearing
other people's story through you you've
got to write your own stories and your
own experiences
number three don't ever guess what the
readers want to read right you have to
write a book for yourself
and if you write a book with which you
fall in love there'll be enough number
of leaders with your sensibilities who
will also fall in love
and that is what i would recommend to
you there is no secret formula it's like
really interesting rajesh you know
because i was in a conversation with
another author yesterday and he said
almost the same thing in some
in few different words he said that i
write for myself and i
and and that is why probably you know i
have this big i write for myself i write
a book that i would love reading again
and again and and that is i think
probably also what you're trying to say
here
and i agree with all of you you know i
agree with all of you i think uh
it is a combination of all of this um
and we spoke about this briefly
yesterday also i think we
also india we as indians have to have
confidence in our ideas
our originality and our success
and our own stories so you know this is
something that
i think slowly and steadily is now
getting reflected in the books that are
coming out which i
believe are of global standards so like
you know india in publishing
particularly always has been this you
know uh
western driven market even in uk
actually a lot of the books business
books
come from us so us has been the market
leader in
in business books so far but i think we
are seeing a lot of local talent now
uh people who are addressing problems
specific to the region
and telling stories that the customers
and readers in that region want to hear
so i wish all of you good luck i hope
you all keep on writing many many more
books
and to also our viewers are watching us
uh do take writing seriously i think
this is something that lives longer than
us like rajesh also put it
and uh and you know our our talent
and our confidence gets reflected in the
books we create
it's a superpower anybody who can write
more than 280 characters it's a
superpower now
yes absolutely we'll move on to the next
question now
and i think this is again you know this
is about i think what
rajesh was talking earlier about
brands like bagpiper and how you made it
successful
ashok wants to know would be interesting
to know how rajesh convinced
all the consumers to drink the image of
back piper though it is an indian blend
it's related to what you're talking
about it's it's it's very very simple uh
ashoka i hope i got your name right you
know uh
we all love shahrukh khan shah rukh
loves pepsi so we love pepsi
i mean uh that's it right
that's all so even now i can remember
graduation's posters right so i didn't
know he was behind it there were chest
programs
i remember
just wanted to share this with you you
know when you create brand don't create
it with your mind make it with your
heart
so this line jamaica rank actually was
created in 1990 so i was invited to a
girls college in
uh in in suburban mumbai and
that's where you got the inspiration
rajesh okay
you know i was to speak on digital media
so i asked the principal
can i talk about alcohol so she asked me
when did you work so i said in 90s
so she looked at the age and she must
have got an idea that they wouldn't know
the brand
so i started by saying you know i give
the name mcdowell signature there was a
big
round of appreciation then i said i
deserve to stand in front of you if i
say two words and you can repeat the
balance tag line
and i said coop jamaica wrong and these
young girls are singing in unison jumble
writing a team yaar
i looked at the principle she wanted to
go down the stage and that's when i
realized
brands you know they transcend time this
was created in 1990s
but the whole point is that if you
create a brand from your heart it
touches other people's heart
wonderful i think you know we have time
for one more question
and for all our other viewers i think
you know you can uh
approach our author directly on their
social media linkedin etc and you know
i'm sure they'll be happy to answer
your questions um the last question is
for you saurabh
can saurabh drop some company names
which are from the 20th century but
effectively using the new rules of
business in the new decade this is from
srikan yoshi
and i know our portfolio companies
inside out so all the names i'm going to
tell you
are are following uh new rules of
business they are following
uh the path to simplicity uh the path to
victory through simplicity
they are indian companies and and
several of them actually building global
dominance
while being small indian companies it's
a very fascinating thing global
dominance
why is being a small indian company so
so let me just give three names from
various various portfolios of the top of
my head there's a company outside pune
called
technical fibers they have 70
market share globally now in salmon
aquaculture fishing nets right this is a
the 20 this is 40 year old company
they started the current promoter took
charge when his father passed away in
the mid 90s
he turned the company around eight nine
years ago he figured out that
salmon fishing nets as they currently
stood eight years back in the west have
a problem
uh the the nylon gets warped uh uh
bacteria sits in there the fish power
the net
the water flow gets disrupted he spoke
to the uh the fisheries in norway
in canada uh worked with chemical
engineers in pune
created a superior net and you have 70
global market share
from an indian company that most people
that don't think in our country have
have heard about let's take another
company
in mumbai called gmm foddler they
control half the global market in glass
lined reactors so glass line reactors
are basically
giant versions of this coffee cup in
which pharmaceutical products are made
fodler was the german parent they used
to own
they used to own 51 percent of gmm in
india gm was the indian subsidiary
uh as the country grew as india grew gm
ended up becoming bigger than the parent
and the indian company ended up buying
the global parent and thus you have a
company mumbai
which has the dream which has which
lives the dream of
half of the world's medicines are now
made in ceramic vessels
uh whose ownership uh basically is india
right simple idea you your
if the indian market becomes larger than
the global parents market
you flip and they the ownership comes to
uh comes to our country
uh and third idea another company that
that and the beauty about these is a lot
of these companies because
they keep a low profile because they are
family owned so the company in chennai
called ultramarine they're the world's
third largest in asia's largest
manufacturer
of literally ultramarine pigment so when
your car is painted when my car is
painted
this pigment has to be put in the paint
because otherwise the sunlight will work
the
work the paint this family in chennai is
the largest manufacturer in
asia of this product uh you cannot paint
cars without this product
and yet they keep the secret to
themselves all of these companies
are indian companies they're world
leaders and this is the new rule of
business
that small indian companies can go and
conquer the world
wow i mean i think it's a great note to
end our discussion today
my apologies to all our viewers whose
questions we could not answer but like i
said
uh our authors and our panelists are
available so you can write to them
directly and reach out to them and i'm
sure they'll
be happy to answer your questions uh
thank you
a big thank you to all our panelists
today rajesh saurabh anupam i had a
great time chatting with all of you
thank you for being so wonderful and
speaking from your heart
and mind and teaching us how to be
simple
yet victorious so thank you so much big
thank you
thank you very much thanks a lot i hope
you enjoy the rest of your evening
thank you everybody thank you so much